<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Flatiron Journey</title>
    <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Flatiron Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 23:23:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://itzsaga.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Asset Pipeline Is Flowing</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-098/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 23:23:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-098/</guid>
      <description>I finally got back into the swing of Flatiron. I did &amp;lt;30 mins of school yesterday so I just chose to blog about FCC. A lot of reading going on as of late. The Rails asset pipeline and how to use it. I actually figured out some of this since I implemented Bootstrap in my Rails Portfolio Project. It felt good to plow through some labs tonight. I&amp;rsquo;m so close. Now is the time to crank up the intensity and really go at it to the finish line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>freeCodeCamp Nashville June Meetup Recap</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/fccnashville-june-meetup-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 20:15:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/fccnashville-june-meetup-recap/</guid>
      <description>We had our June meetup today and it was good. A small group but we solved some problems together and we talked shop some. Specifically, Leland brought up the scope of the projects. How it&amp;rsquo;s easy to go off on tangents and hours later be so far away from what you initially started working on. We shared some tips on how to stay focused and keep within the scope of the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening Day of Music City Code</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-095/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 22:29:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-095/</guid>
      <description>This morning came way too soon after last night. However, today was good. Got to see Jest in action. Saw a simple Hapi.js server. Learned about Wallaby.js. Got to do some planning for our table tomorrow and Saturday. Got 3 lessons/labs done in Flatiron and finished the Advanced JS section. It was good. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to tomorrow. However, I will not get sidetracked like I did last night and actually get to bet before 11pm tonight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Assessment In The Books!</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-094/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 23:03:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-094/</guid>
      <description>I passed my Rails Assessment today! It went well and there was only one thing I needed to follow up with after it was over. Now I&amp;rsquo;m just looking for the check mark on it to turn green!
The next few days are going to be LONG. However, they should be very productive and great networking. They&amp;rsquo;ll be long because they start EARLY (like be there at 7am early) and I still plan on coding at night once the kiddos go to bed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocha, Chai, or Just Some Jasmine?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-093/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:13:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-093/</guid>
      <description>I just spent way too much time looking into Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, and I can&amp;rsquo;t remember what other test libraries. Trying to solve this testing problem we have over in Javscripting that I help maintain. I like the fact that there&amp;rsquo;s this problem that needs to be solved and it&amp;rsquo;s something I can learn from. Now I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out how to test against a file that has no functions in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduation Sprint Time</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-092/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 23:13:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-092/</guid>
      <description>So I had a bunch of stuff to say, okay not really, and then I checked my Dashboard on Learn and saw the beautiful sight that my Graduation Dashboard has appeared! That means I&amp;rsquo;m past 75% done and in the final stretch. Being 75% done in &amp;lt;3 months has me on track to be done before the end of June! I&amp;rsquo;m stoked.
So something that I had been struggling with is how Ruby is a class-based object-oriented language and JavaScript is a prototype based object-oriented language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Mustache You A Question</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-091/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 22:52:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-091/</guid>
      <description>Yes I just made that joke. However, I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of a Handlebars.js lab so I think it&amp;rsquo;s fitting.
 Handlebars uses the curly brace as a delimiter because if you turn it sideways it looks like a mustache, and Handlebars.js is an extension of the Mustache template language.
 Today was a lot of HTML, CSS, and Templating so no new notes on anything. I find that HTML &amp;amp; CSS stick pretty well and until I&amp;rsquo;m actually using a templating language in a project I won&amp;rsquo;t take notes just yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>90 Days Goes Fast in the Dev World</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-090/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 22:55:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-090/</guid>
      <description>Zero lessons or labs done yesterday. Had an impromptu dinner at the in-laws and when my wife and I got home we decided to spend some time with the neighbors talking. That turned into a great evening or wine, scotch, and conversation until 4am. I did however, read You Don&amp;rsquo;t Know JS in the car on the way to and from dinner so I did some learning. I got through the first book, Up &amp;amp; Going, and was able to start the second book, Scope &amp;amp; Closures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DOM &amp; Oh My Zsh!</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-088/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 23:13:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-088/</guid>
      <description>The DOM. Forgot to throw in the main info about the DOM I learned yesterday in last night&amp;rsquo;s blog:
  The Document Object Model is a representation of the current view of the browser, and can be manipulated without reloading a page. The HTML is the text in a file first used to display the page.  With Javascript we can (1) view a current representation of our Document Object Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Be Strict</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-087/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 23:02:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-087/</guid>
      <description>Today I spent 30 mins pairing with one of the Learn instructors trying to work through some issues my Rails portfolio project has. Something I found out is that the project requirement to use a custom attribute writer instead of has_nested_attributes actually removes some functionality from the final app. Because of this lack of Rails magic one of my problems is harder to fix than expected. The other one is just a more simple if.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ruby = [], ruby &lt;&lt; javascript</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-086/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 23:06:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-086/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript is coming back to me more and more as I&amp;rsquo;m getting back into it. I have to say it&amp;rsquo;s a bit frustrating at times but that&amp;rsquo;s fine. I look back at how Ruby was frustrating when I started and how I enjoy it so much now (most of the time). Okay. I&amp;rsquo;m beat. It was a long day. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll even publish this tonight because it&amp;rsquo;s not even a full paragraph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-085/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 23:06:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-085/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;m back in JavaScript world again. Since I had done a lot of the intro stuff during my Bootcamp Prep work I spent tonight mostly skimming over everything I already had done to remind my mind how to think JS. I have to say, it didn&amp;rsquo;t come back quickly when I was reading it. The first lab I worked on, well the only lab I worked on, was slow. However, the functions and syntax came quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs and Testing and Coverage</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-084/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 22:44:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-084/</guid>
      <description>I tidied up my app today. I decided to scrub the DB and run a new set of seeds then test everything as best I could. This is where I see automated testing is very useful. I really want to get better acquainted with writing tests. However, I also want to finish this curriculum so I can stop paying tuition. I&amp;rsquo;m slowly building out my testing resources to take a deeper dive into that once I&amp;rsquo;m done with Flatiron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did I Really Finish Rails?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/did-i-really-finish-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 18:45:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/did-i-really-finish-rails/</guid>
      <description>My Rails project is officially done! Well, it officially fulfills all the requirements that Flatiron School has for it. I definitely have more to do with it. However, considering that I&amp;rsquo;m done almost a day and a half before my self set deadline I&amp;rsquo;m happy. Some minor things in my views (like showing just a user&amp;rsquo;s items instead of all items), building out a more robust navbar, filling out my readme, and I should be good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitting A Wall &amp; Making A Plan</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-082/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 23:40:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-082/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m stuck. It&amp;rsquo;s no fun. I still have things to try but I&amp;rsquo;ve hit a wall. It&amp;rsquo;s to be expected and the nested form I&amp;rsquo;m working on is by no means a simple thing. However, this is basically the BIG problem in this project. In my opinion at least this is the hardest part of this project.
 Include a nested form writing to an associated model using a custom attribute writer (form URL, model name e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails &amp; Bootstrap &amp; Font Awesome</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-081/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 23:09:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-081/</guid>
      <description>Today was productive. I was able to create a more in depth TODO file during the day while I was watching my kiddos. This allowed me to think more about how my app was going to function and what I needed/wanted to build into it. It provided me with a better workflow for the evening. I knew exactly what I would be working on tonight. Even if I did get sidetracked a couple times while working it was still always productive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Think I Can, I Think I Can...</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-080/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 23:30:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-080/</guid>
      <description>Man, it&amp;rsquo;s hard keeping track of all the tools I&amp;rsquo;m using as I&amp;rsquo;m building out this app. I&amp;rsquo;m finding the biggest thing I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on right now is getting Devise to look nice by customizing the views and implementing Bootstrap 4. One thing I had to work on was updating the strong params in Devise so my User could register with name. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t too tricky although I&amp;rsquo;m implementing it &amp;ldquo;the lazy way™&amp;rdquo; which I&amp;rsquo;m okay with for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Project is Underway</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-079/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 23:27:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-079/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much done yesterday so I ended up not writing. I did figure out an app to build for my project. However, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get much done in the way of getting started. I won&amp;rsquo;t get into it, but, I was frustrated with last night.
Tonight has been better. I&amp;rsquo;m making progress setting the base of the app up. It took a little bit to figure out how to setup PostgreSQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Project Here I Come</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-077/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 23:50:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-077/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m officially ready to start my Rails Portfolio Project! Woot woot! I still don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do for it so I&amp;rsquo;m going to read the requirements tonight and brainstorm through the day tomorrow so I can start tomorrow night. I&amp;rsquo;ll also bring this up in the weekly stand up tomorrow morning and see if I can get some ideas.
I had a couple unique problems today, at least unique to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Projects &amp; RubyMine</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-076/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 23:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-076/</guid>
      <description>Today was long but good. I started off by hosting my first study group. Turns some people really do get some coding done on the weekends even if Slack is much quieter. We had a good talk and it was an easy way to start the day.
I got through the Pundit lab which took way longer than I thought it would but that was fine. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I was beating my head against a well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful or Not?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-075/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 23:17:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-075/</guid>
      <description>So last night I chose not to write a post. I attended a study group that walked through the lab I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing tomorrow on Pundit and watched a lecture. Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t do any actual writing of code I skipped the blog. However, I know how to solve the Pundit lab quickly now ;-).
I started tonight off helping out my man Mike (we did the Music Library CLI project together) setup his associations for this Sinatra portfolio project (see above).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CanCanCan? I Thought It Was Can Can?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-073/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 23:06:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-073/</guid>
      <description>I spent a lot of time yesterday and today psyching myself out about this Devise lab. Turns out it was very straightforward. All the extra &amp;ldquo;research&amp;rdquo; I was doing was actually taking away from me getting it done. When I reset myself and approached the lab like all the others I got through it quickly.
 Follow ReadMe. Run tests. Look at spec for first test. Get first test to pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devise Is A Beast</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-072/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 23:12:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-072/</guid>
      <description>Today I started my Devise learning. I was feeling pretty good until I realized the teaching had stopped and I still had 10 failing tests with no way to solve them. I figured out how to pass one of the tests. I even had it passing. However, I decided to rollback my code as I had literally just been copying and pasting stuff in and I&amp;rsquo;m sure my code was all over the place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OAuth Just Makes Sense, Now</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-071/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 23:10:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-071/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m progressing through Rails Authentication and am happy that I completed the Omniauth section today. It was my goal and I hit it. Tomorrow I start tackling Devise. Something about OAuth that makes a lot more sense to me now is letting someone else worry about the user and their data (to an extent). I can locally store a password or I can let someone else worry about the security and I can just use that third party to verify a person is who they say they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Keep It Safe With Authentication</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-070/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 23:04:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-070/</guid>
      <description>It was a strong day and I moved into Authentication. Authentication is going to be a beast I can tell. However, it looks like because it&amp;rsquo;s such an important topic there are a lot of best practices and good documentation out there. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t wrapped my head around the Sessions Controller 100% but knowing that it was almost identical in 3 separate labs tells me it&amp;rsquo;s a relatively static and consistent concept for what I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails is Moving Along</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-069/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 23:27:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-069/</guid>
      <description>Not as much time spent on my curriculum as a typical Saturday but that&amp;rsquo;s alright. It&amp;rsquo;s because of the freeCodeCamp meetup that I Co-Organize (see previous post from earlier today). I still feel accomplished. I&amp;rsquo;m at a point in the Rails section where I have 4 videos then I&amp;rsquo;m on the last section before the projects. Tomorrow will be telling as to if I&amp;rsquo;ll hit my goal of starting my Rails projects on the 10th or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>freeCodeCamp Nashville May Meetup Recap</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/fccnashville-may-meetup-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 17:26:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/fccnashville-may-meetup-recap/</guid>
      <description>So today Dave Harned and I hosted the monthly freeCodeCamp Nashville Meetup. There were 8 of us there and it was good to see new and &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; faces. I think we&amp;rsquo;re starting to build more of a core group that will consistently attend the meetup. With that we&amp;rsquo;ve started exploring some other options for larger meetup locations. The library is nice but the wifi is awfully slow and that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big downside considering what we&amp;rsquo;re meeting for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rubocop Saves The Day</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-068/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 23:12:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-068/</guid>
      <description>I missed writing yesterday. However, I chose to skip the writing while I enjoyed a very productive study group. Not really. We chatted about everything except code mostly because nobody really showed up at the proper time for it. After 3 hours of talking it was late and I decided to not write a blog post.
I also went to a Ruby meetup last night. It was underwhelming this month with only 3 of us in attendance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Render Partial New Mouse, What?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-066/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 22:38:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-066/</guid>
      <description>Cut it short tonight. Needed to. Learned some more about rendering partials tonight. Main takeaway code example &amp;lt;%= render partial: &#39;songs/song_details&#39;, collection: @genre.songs, as: :song %&amp;gt; will iterate through @genre.songs and passes those objects to the partial as song.
My wife bought be a trackball mouse :-)
Prepped some of my possible presentation on REST for Saturday.
That&amp;rsquo;s all I got.
Time spent today: 1:34
Time spent total: 248:16
Lessons completed today: 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partials of Collections? They&#39;re Awesome.</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-065/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 22:54:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-065/</guid>
      <description>Partials are coming together more and I have to say they&amp;rsquo;re pretty sweet. Rails does some automagical stuff that I can&amp;rsquo;t completely wrap my head around just yet. However, I probably won&amp;rsquo;t be able to for a while as the people who created it are WAY smarter than me. However, as an example there&amp;rsquo;s this sequence of things that Rails does:
&amp;lt;% @posts.each do |post| %&amp;gt; &amp;lt;%= render :partial =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;post&amp;quot;, {:locals =&amp;gt; {:post =&amp;gt; post}} %&amp;gt; &amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Partially Understand Partials</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-064/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 22:51:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-064/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I thought Rails layouts and templates would be somewhat easy. While in a sense it&amp;rsquo;s taking snippets and putting them in other files to reuse of course there has to be some logic in there to ensure that the proper data is being shown. So rendering partials with locals is starting to make sense.
For my example &amp;lt;%= render partial: &amp;quot;authors/author&amp;quot;, locals: {author: @author} %&amp;gt; - The first key-value pair partial: &amp;quot;authors/author&amp;quot; tells Rails the name of the partial to render.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pieces Are Coming Together</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-063/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 22:01:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-063/</guid>
      <description>Feeling great about today. The things that a struggled with the most I ended up cementing (it&amp;rsquo;s not dry yet) into my brain. The Learn community is awesome I must say. After 2 hours with a Learn Expert (basically a TA) we were both sufficiently stumped. I dropped a note into the students Slack channel and &amp;lt;20 minutes it was figured out by the group. So you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering what it was&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in Flow and Go</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-062/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 22:57:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-062/</guid>
      <description>It felt so good to spend almost the entire day coding. I missed it. My progress was VERY SLOW at times (or so it felt). Things like the :source option in Active Record were foreign and not really taught but needed to solve a large lab I was working on starting first thing this morning. Luckily I have access to some awesome help. Here&amp;rsquo;s one conversation I had today:
 Seth Alexander 34 MINUTES AGO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding While Sleeping. Is That Possible?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-061/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 22:59:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-061/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to be very happy to code during the day tomorrow. I&amp;rsquo;ve been tired these last few nights during my target of 8pm - 11pm coding time. I just took a second, leaned back in my chair so my head could rest on the chair back, closed my eyes to think about a problem, and almost fell asleep.
Learned about some Active Record Callbacks of which there are many more than I would have imagined:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo Day &amp; Join the FBI?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-060/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 23:27:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-060/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m exhausted tonight. Been working mainly on more Active Record associations. More complex ones than before I would assume to get in practice for later labs. Foreign key and Class Name Active Record class methods to be exact if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for some light reading lol.
I attended an Alumni career fair at my alma matter Belmont University today which was interesting. I never attended one as an undergrad so the whole, drop your resume off on as many tables as possible, was lost on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Forget to Check the Password</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-059/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 23:07:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-059/</guid>
      <description>Watching Avi build out the TodoMVC is an interesting thing and I&amp;rsquo;m happy I get to do it as part of my curriculum and showing what Rails does. That was the bulk of the new work I did tonight. Something that I ran into during my Sinatra project was getting all my associations to work properly. I had issues because of what I now know is called the Active Record Inflector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Params Can Change</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-058/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 23:35:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-058/</guid>
      <description>Not much going on but completing a couple larger labs tonight. One significant things that halted me for a while was an issue in my strong params. I had:
def song_params params.permit(:title, :released, :release_year, :artist_name, :genre) end  Which looks really nice but doesn&amp;rsquo;t take into account that I&amp;rsquo;m using form_for and thus my submitted data is actually a nested hash. A quick change to:
def song_params params.require(:song).permit(:title, :released, :release_year, :artist_name, :genre) end  Had me moving along again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Speaker-Listener Technique</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-057/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 23:02:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-057/</guid>
      <description>I can happily say that I got zero, yes 0 coding done today. Well I guess I got a little in during my 45 minutes Sinatra Project review this morning. Which was a great review btw.
 Hi Seth,
Awesome job on your Sinatra Project!! You did a great job, and I really appreciate your work on the Active Record relationships and your clean and concise code. As you move forward these practices will help you a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Is Short. Code Hard.</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-056/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 22:31:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-056/</guid>
      <description>So that intense lab I was talking about yesterday&amp;hellip; it took no time at all because of Rails. It was AWESOME. One of the things I learned today that is going to make life easier and ensure DRY.
# example_controller.rb # Insert at top of controller before_action :set_example, only: [:show, :edit, :update, :destroy] # Insert at end of controller private def set_example @example = Example.find(params[:id]) end  So up until now to access a db object as an instance variable I&amp;rsquo;ve used the ID passed in from the URL or form and then done a lookup to set the instance variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Problems Makes You Stronger</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-055/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 23:24:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-055/</guid>
      <description>It was a LONG day on my computer. Ubuntu decided to suggest I update to 16.10 and I did. Well that just started a string of issues that ended up in me reinstalling 16.04.2 LTS. I lost my entire morning and early afternoon to this process before I could get coding today. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I could&amp;rsquo;ve figured it out in time but time is something that is precious and I really had no need to upgrade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Makes Life Easier but Difficult</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-054/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 23:20:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-054/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with Rails. I now have 5 pages in my Cast Iron Design notebook. Something cool that I learned today:
&amp;lt;!-- How link_to works --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;% @posts.each do |post| %&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;%= link_to post.title, post_path(post) %&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- Creates the following HTML --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/posts/1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;My Title&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;  Which is pretty sweet considering how I was doing it in Sinatra. Something else that&amp;rsquo;s pretty sweet is that when we code post_path(post) Rails is smart enough to know that it needs to use the id attribute of the post object we just passed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fog is in the Brain</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-053/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 22:44:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-053/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is tonight but I just can&amp;rsquo;t get into the groove. I&amp;rsquo;m steady distracted and not focused. And no it&amp;rsquo;s not because of the date, you know you were thinking it. Ugh. At least it&amp;rsquo;s on a &amp;ldquo;short&amp;rdquo; day and I did attend a meetup tonight so I did something beneficial to my coding journey that took a few hours of my evening. I am a few pages into one of my notebooks though so I can say that&amp;rsquo;s good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yay! You&#39;re on Rails!</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-052/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 23:22:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-052/</guid>
      <description>Today I started Rails in all it&amp;rsquo;s glory. This will be my first full on framework that I get to work with. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen though it&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that has so much the key will be to stay focused on what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to have Rails do instead of everything it can do. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy to think that after this large section Career Services will be reaching out to me to start that process while I finished up the JS part of the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Deployed My Sinatra App To Heroku</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 23:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</guid>
      <description>MY SINATRA PORTFOLIO PROJECT IS DONE!!!
You can say I&amp;rsquo;m pretty stoked. This blog is part of the requirements though so get ready :-). Actually, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take enough notes to really get into the code in this blog. I did hit some solid stumbling blocks and there is some major refactoring of code needing to happen but I&amp;rsquo;m overall pretty happy. A large part of the time I spent was making the app look good utilizing Bootstrap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you Gifted?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-050/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 23:19:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-050/</guid>
      <description>Not much to report today. I got some free passes from being a member of American Mensa to see Gifted. So the wife and I went to see that tonight. It&amp;rsquo;s a good movie and I recommend it.
I finished up the controller and views for one part of my Sinatra project. It&amp;rsquo;s coming along nicely. Now that I have this done I don&amp;rsquo;t think the next two controllers and associated views will take as long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Easter</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-049/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 22:05:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-049/</guid>
      <description>I decided to take the weekend off and enjoy the Easter holiday with the family. I had been going hard for almost 7 straight weeks. Back at it tomorrow. I also ordered my Code &amp;amp; Quill Origin this weekend. Looking forward to getting my notebooks just in time to take notes on Rails.
Time spent today: 0:00
Time spent total: 188:40
Lessons completed today: 0
Lessons completed total: 405</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It Look nice</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-047/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 23:07:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-047/</guid>
      <description>So about that not being fancy that I talked about last night. I took a good chunk of time today and figured out how to implement Bootstrap in my portfolio project. I figured this was my first web app and should probably look somewhat nice. I have a navbar that changes if you&amp;rsquo;re logged in or not and then I&amp;rsquo;m using the form and typography stylings. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely taking me longer to write my forms out and I&amp;rsquo;m making sure my app actually will look good so that is taking more time as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crushing Fwitter Tonight was Sweet</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-046/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 23:44:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-046/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s late so I&amp;rsquo;ll be brief. I crushed my project tonight and I&amp;rsquo;m ready to start my Sinatra portfolio project tomorrow. I think I can have an ugly version (desktown down design, raw forms, no nav bar or footer) done tomorrow at some point and then leave it alone until after my project review with an instructor. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes. The requirements are:
 Build an MVC Sinatra Application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing it Down Always Helps</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-045/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 23:10:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-045/</guid>
      <description>Taking it easy tonight. I have to get some work done for Gift of Adoption Fund, the non-profit I volunteer on the board for here in TN. Shameless plug, Like our Facebook Page please. I finished up the NYC lab in &amp;lt;30 minutes. The second controller and views were much more simple. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to refactor my code yet. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t think a helper methods are needed as I didn&amp;rsquo;t use that code anywhere in my other controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helper Methods Tested, How to Not Repeat Yourself</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-044/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 23:16:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-044/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on a killer roll right now blowing through this NYC lab. Built my 3 tables and 1 JOIN table migrations. Built out the associated models. Built out all the views and one controller. Have one controller and it&amp;rsquo;s views left now. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t have kids that were going to wake me up between 6:30am and 8:00am I&amp;rsquo;d finish it up. I think it&amp;rsquo;ll take me maybe 30 more mins (mostly because A LOT of it is going to be similar to the controller &amp;amp; views I just built) but sleep is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Playlister with Quick Superior Code</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-043/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 23:29:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-043/</guid>
      <description>Got a large lab done tonight. Right on schedule. I was done 2 minutes after 11pm. I basically took the Music Library CLI app that I made earlier in the curriculum and turned it into a much more user friendly Sinatra MVC web app. The final code can be found here. The biggest challenge I had was setting up my databases and models. Actually, just with the JOIN table. However, I know the more I do this the easier it will get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching Through Roadblocks Quickly is Monumental Now</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-042/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 23:22:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-042/</guid>
      <description>Today was the day of road blocks. I spent probably 3 hours working with Learn Experts on problems. For the most part these were dev environment issues or weird test issues and not working through my code and learning new things. I did learn some things about debugging though. I learned to check my Gemfile because if a gem is missing weird things happen. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how I was able to run shotgun without having the gem in the Gemfile but it worked and then I got odd errors in my browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I suddenly know how it all fits together better.</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-041/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 23:21:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-041/</guid>
      <description>I moved through a lot of curriculum today. However, I really want to hit the goal I set two weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m on the cusp of it! I had 21 lessons/labs to go for my goal when I checked early in the day. So I set a goal of 11 more today (I had laready finished 2) and finish tomorrow. I missed it by one only because it&amp;rsquo;s late and I hit an hour and a half review lecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do recruiters make you mad? What&#39;s your advice?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-040/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 23:02:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-040/</guid>
      <description>So nested forms aren&amp;rsquo;t as bad as I thought they would be. I guess it helps that I had some good teaching before I got into it. I think I had the longest video yet to watch tonight and that took up most of the time once I finished the lab I started last night. The lab I&amp;rsquo;m on seems to be more of the same just getting the concept to stick with a more in depth nested form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Take it Easy Sometimes and Still Win</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-039/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 22:29:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-039/</guid>
      <description>I only got a little bit of coding done tonight by choice. I think I&amp;rsquo;m procrastinating on this nested hash forms lab because nested hashes can get confusing. I started it though and just got sidetracked. I need to stay focused. I worked on getting RubyMine installed to see what it&amp;rsquo;s about and my computer froze. After that I just gave up on coding tonight. I guess I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very motivated if that&amp;rsquo;s all it took lol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 38</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-038/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 23:15:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-038/</guid>
      <description>Sinatra, and models, and views, and controllers, and erb, OH MY! Tonight I kept building small things with Sinatra. I&amp;rsquo;ve realized exactly how the MVC system works and what each piece does. The model is all the ruby classes I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing. The view is a mixture of HTML and Ruby that the user sees in their browser. The controller takes the user input and returns the data that has been crunched by the models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 37</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-037/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 23:11:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-037/</guid>
      <description>Sinatra is moving along and clicking well. I have this fear after being somewhat cocky in last night&amp;rsquo;s post that the spirits of those Senior Devs before me are going to jump into my learning and humble me some. If so, not today. It&amp;rsquo;s all making sense the first time through. I think this is because there&amp;rsquo;s very little new logic. It&amp;rsquo;s just where to put that login in regards to models, views and controllers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 36</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-036/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 22:59:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-036/</guid>
      <description>I got a late start tonight :-( so I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend as much time as I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked. However, I did learn that my wife did not know that it was not a good idea to try and peel a cantaloupe with a chef&amp;rsquo;s knife. Yeah, so after helping her wrap a sliced finger in a paper towel cantaloupe slicing duty fell on me. Then I spilled my tea all over my desk because one of my children (I&amp;rsquo;m guessing the 2 year old) had wedged my chair under my desk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 35</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-035/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 21:45:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-035/</guid>
      <description>Progress progress progress. I&amp;rsquo;m moving along. I watched the last ActiveRecord video then finished up the Rack section. Learning the lowest level of how Rails runs a webserver. There is a granular procedure that&amp;rsquo;s happening and it was explained. First we learn basic Rack, then Sinatra abstracts a little bit more, then Rails abstracts even more. So when things do break, because they will, there is an understanding of what&amp;rsquo;s actually going on to fix it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 34</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-034/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 23:00:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-034/</guid>
      <description>It was a good day in the coding world of Seth. I started out completing a decent size lab in the ActiveRecord section. Then headed off to the Free Code Camp Nashville meetup. It was a great meetup where Jason Gresalfi presented on how he had created a Chrome extension. The repo for his extentsion can be found here and you can find it in the Chrome webstore here. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; chrome extensions can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 33</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-033/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:26:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-033/</guid>
      <description>I started Active Record tonight and I&amp;rsquo;m stoked. Mostly because a lot of the work has already been done and now I can just use the magic that is provided to me. I think I have always had the basic understanding that there are libraries that will be doing a lot of the things I have been learning for me. That is why when I get stuck on things but can still complete projects and labs I just push through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Learning Hacks</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/my-learning-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 23:28:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/my-learning-hacks/</guid>
      <description>So I wanted to share the hacks that I&amp;rsquo;m using to upgrade my life some and increase my mental aptitude to crushing this curriculum. There is a certain amount of mental stamina that has to be maintained on a day to day basis to keep up this pace. So&amp;hellip; here&amp;rsquo;s my brain upgrades/biohacks/etc&amp;hellip; that keep my moving tip top while doing this bootcamp full time and taking care of kids full time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 32</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-032/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 22:38:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-032/</guid>
      <description>Almost 3 hours of review vidoes watched tonight. On thing that I think can be very useful to all. A double bang !! converts an object to it&amp;rsquo;s truthy value. For example:
seth@seth-u:~$ irb 2.4.0 :001 &amp;gt; 1 =&amp;gt; 1 2.4.0 :002 &amp;gt; !1 =&amp;gt; false 2.4.0 :003 &amp;gt; !!1 =&amp;gt; true  So the return value of 1 is 1 we know 1 has a boolean value of true. So !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 31</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-031/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 23:18:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-031/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I had my CLI Gem Project review with one of the instructors. It was pretty cool. I talked through my project from start to almost finish (I realized after we finished we never went over the last method that takes user input to either start over or end). We added another class and refactored some code to make my gen more extensible and flexible in the future. While they&amp;rsquo;re not official tasks I set a couple new features I want to add to the gem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 30</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-030/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 23:15:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-030/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I was able to get much deeper into the ORM section. The curriculum returned to the lesson then lab format that is more familiar. Learn how to build a few methods and why you build them that way. Then immediately do it locally. Then the next lesson builds on the last. This is much easier to make progress through and I feel much better about databases now. Well, I feel much better about how they integrate and how Ruby wraps them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 29</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-029/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 23:14:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-029/</guid>
      <description>Polished off the SQL tonight and I have to say it was more in depth than I thought it would be. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that is hard to visualize being new to it. When the tables are laid out in a grid it all makes sense but just trying to do it all in your head is confusing, even for me. I&amp;rsquo;m sure if I was doing it every day it would be much more intuitive but right now I&amp;rsquo;m still a little fuzzy on keeping track of the data I&amp;rsquo;m looking for through multiple JOINS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 28</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-028/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 23:41:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-028/</guid>
      <description>Today started with multiple review videos on the CLI Gem Project. I also was able to schedule my project review for Wednesday night. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to some one-on-one time with an instructor talking through my code. The project states:
 BE PREPARED TO:
1. Explain your code from execution point to exit point. We&amp;rsquo;re making sure you wrote it and understand how it works, nothing else. 10-20 minutes 2. Refactor code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 27</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-027/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 23:57:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-027/</guid>
      <description>So I went later than I wanted to tonight, but I was on a roll. I would have finished much earlier but I spent 2.5 hours today at a developer meetup. It was interesting as I&amp;rsquo;ve only been to one other so far. It was good to meet some people and start putting real people to the dev community in Nashville. I did find out that basically nobody is learning/using Ruby (at least at this meetup).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 26</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-026/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 22:46:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-026/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I made some good progress on my CLI project. I finished watching Avi&amp;rsquo;s video on the project and it helped A LOT. It was long so I decided to just complete the basic stub of my project and leave it at that for tonight. I really like working with fake placeholder data for as long as possible. This way it&amp;rsquo;ll all hopefully just work when real data is passed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 25</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 23:11:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-025/</guid>
      <description>So tonight I started my CLI Gem project. This one is going to be in my portfolio and has A LOT more to it. Okay, well maybe not a lot more but it&amp;rsquo;s the first time I&amp;rsquo;m starting from scratch to build something. Luckily, I&amp;rsquo;m not left out to dry and there is a how-to that&amp;rsquo;s over an hour long that Avi did. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly what I&amp;rsquo;ll need to do and I&amp;rsquo;ll run into problems along the way but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a good resource to start with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 24</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 23:01:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-024/</guid>
      <description>yawn it&amp;rsquo;s been a long day. My 3 month old was up early today. Either way, I got my scraping project done tonight. Nokogiri can be quite particular about the things you use to select content. Turned out I was pretty much there and just needed to change how I was accessing the info I needed.
Attended a Study Group tonight which taught me something very important. When using pry inside a loop when you enter exit into the pry prompt it runs the next loop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 23</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 23:15:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-023/</guid>
      <description>So working on my scraping project. It&amp;rsquo;s hurting my head. Scraping is no fun to figure out. What I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on right now is iterating. When I have some time tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m going to work on completely understanding iterating when scraping. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m looking at currently:
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;social-icon-container&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/empireofryan&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;quot;social-icon&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;../assets/img/twitter-icon.png&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-johnson-321629ab&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;quot;social-icon&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;../assets/img/linkedin-icon.png&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://github.com/empireofryan&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;quot;social-icon&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;../assets/img/github-icon.png&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C22ufOqDyaE&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;quot;social-icon&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;../assets/img/rss-icon.png&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;  Then I&amp;rsquo;m doing (among other things above it):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 22</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 22:51:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-022/</guid>
      <description>About 10 minutes before I was suppose to get to my computer the power went out in my subdivision. I quickly realized that while I had setup flashlights in strategic locations in our apartment, when we moved into our house I never did the same. My wife and I both did not have our phones on us and it was DARK. Needless to say I closed the baby gate at the top of the stairs to keep the little ones safe and made my way to the kitchen where I knew a flashlight was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 21</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 22:32:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-021/</guid>
      <description>Another productive project day means, not much to talk about! I got through all the tests that I needed to for my Tic-Tac-Toe with AI project. I started trying to build out my &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; but didn&amp;rsquo;t get very far. I know I need to start simple so I decided to just attempt the computer making random moves. I tried to implement the following work flow: 1. Get the current board array (although this should be passed in by default).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Way To Pair Program</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/one-way-to-pair-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 23:07:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/one-way-to-pair-program/</guid>
      <description>Tonight a couple people were wanting to know the best way to pair program together. They had both done the beginning parts of the Tic-Tac-Toe with AI project (the one I&amp;rsquo;m getting ready to start) and wanted to work on the AI part together. The exact question was:
 Hey @*** and I are doing parallel pairing :slightly_smiling_face: what is the best way to go about this, to work on the same repo on separate branches or just copy on paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 20</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 22:57:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-020/</guid>
      <description>Sorry I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a blog in yesterday. I was struggling with setting up a dual boot of Ubuntu on my Windows 10 laptop. I ran into the problem of not having a large enough partition created and hit a snag. That said everything was installing fine once I got going. I had hoped to just run a persistent USB key and be able to take my dev environment wherever I want but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure that out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 18</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 23:21:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-018/</guid>
      <description>Today saw a lot of new stuff. I feel like a ton of stuff was introduced and not gone over very deeply but deep enough for me to understand and implement it. In 11 lessons and labs I was exposed to super and how to use it, mass assignments, creating and implementing custom errors, gems, bundler, and basic scraping with Nokogiri. I can tell I was exposed to many things in preparation for the first projects, which can&amp;rsquo;t get here fast enough!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 23:16:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-017/</guid>
      <description>Tonight was good. I like having a dedicated 3 hour block at night instead of 1 hour in the morning and 2 hours at night. I feel like I can get into a better flow and get more done. I did a study group tonight on a banking lab that I had worked on recently. Took away from it to utilize self on pretty much all instance variable references after they have been initialized (created).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 23:13:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-016/</guid>
      <description>I completely missed my 6am wake up this morning. I realized I didn&amp;rsquo;t reset my alarm from Sunday night. Since I was up until 1am Sunday night I changed my alarm so I could get more sleep. However, thinking about it now having finished tonight at 11pm instead of 10pm I think I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it this way. No matter what I know after 8pm I can be productive. My wife is home and the kids are suppose to be in bed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 15</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 22:22:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-015/</guid>
      <description>Day 15 and I&amp;rsquo;m still here. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t see it I wrote a rather long blog post today as one of my requirements for Flatiron. Since that took up over an hour and I had a 1:10.00+ video as a lesson I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much done. However, I DO have notes from the past couple of days that I never took the time to share.
So on Saturday morning I did a study group with some people and learned a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Software Development?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/why-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 19:40:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/why-software-development/</guid>
      <description>So as part of my bootcamp experience Flatiron School requires me to write blog posts. This is a feature that I don&amp;rsquo;t think all bootcamps have but is smart. If I can write about coding then I show a deeper understanding about why I am a job ready developer. We all know that our online presence is part of our &amp;ldquo;resume&amp;rdquo; now as more and more hiring managers are looking at social profiles when making job decisions (even if it&amp;rsquo;s a [legal slippery slope&amp;hellip;][1]).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 14</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:42:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-014/</guid>
      <description>I promise a good blog post soon. It&amp;rsquo;s almost 1am after a LONG pair programming session, thanks Mike! We did however figure out a hard lab. I would&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with it for sure. It&amp;rsquo;s not as ambiguous as it could be and we didn&amp;rsquo;t break down our methods as much as we could. However, we got all 15 tests passing and learned some new methods along the way. Specifically, the Dir class methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 13</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 21:15:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-013/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m keeping the update short and sweet tonight. I got A LOT done today. However, my amazing wife has let me code all day and into the night on her birthday. Anything important I took notes on today I&amp;rsquo;ll throw in tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s post. It&amp;rsquo;s time to spend some time with her.
Time spent today: 9:15
Time spent total: 56:35
Lessons completed today: 13
Lessons completed total: 247</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 12</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 21:43:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-012/</guid>
      <description>Today didn&amp;rsquo;t see much coding. Mostly because the Intro to Object Oriented Ruby is a 1:10.00 video by of Avi teaching the basics of OO Ruby. Which was good. I found that him talking through concepts made them more clear as I worked on just a couple labs afterwards. It also meant that I took some notes on things that I thought were most important.
Notes which of course I&amp;rsquo;ll share:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 11</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 22:12:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-011/</guid>
      <description>Today was strong work. I finished Procedural Ruby! Now I have Object Oriented Ruby which has final projects and I&amp;rsquo;m done with the Ruby section! I have to say it started to feel like I wasn&amp;rsquo;t making progress but the last two days have reinvigorated me. I know it gets more complex as I go and the projects get bigger and take longer but the groove is starting to fall in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 07:31:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-010/</guid>
      <description>I got a lot done this morning. Especially after the coffee kicked in. When I started I was definitely not 100% awake. I even did some extra credit on a lab which I typically do not do. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been the type to want to score 105 on a test because I aced it AND the extra credit. I did this one specifically because I knew it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t take much time as I was writing a generic method for a specific method I had just completed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 22:15:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-009/</guid>
      <description>Today was a slow day. The kids didn&amp;rsquo;t cooperate this morning and I got zero coding done before all three children were awake. That&amp;rsquo;s fine though. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect every day to go perfectly to plan. It was actually a nice refresher day not starting with coding but still getting the rest of my morning routine done.
I did get in my night time session (minus a few minutes for good night kisses).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 07:40:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-008/</guid>
      <description>Started the day off with a win before 8 am. I was working on a lab to take an array and return a string with Oxford commas inserted. I finished the lab and had it passing tests then refactored and chopped two lines of code out of it. This made me happy.
Original code:
def oxford_comma(array) if array.length == 1 return &amp;quot;#{array[0]}&amp;quot; elsif array.length == 2 return array.join(&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;) elsif array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 22:05:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-007/</guid>
      <description>After 3 hours today I finished up the HTML and CSS section. I took one real note today in that 3 hours:
When it comes to Bootstrap as a framework the .col-xs class never stacks vertically no matter how small the width of the screen gets. Figured that was something I might need to know later. I also learned a lot about how powerful and easy it is to make a site responsive using Bootstrap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 23:00:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-006/</guid>
      <description>It was a LONG day of HTML &amp;amp; CSS and I&amp;rsquo;m still not done with this section. It&amp;rsquo;s okay though. While a lot of it has been review a lot of it has not as well. I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning a ton about responsive web design. Especially Mobile Up (Mobile First) design and how to utilize @media queries in CSS to set break points. As well as some best practices doing design of this type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 04:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-005/</guid>
      <description>Today had a rough start. We decided to start potty training today and my wife and I were not on the same page about what that would look like in terms of the amount of coding I would get done today. Thankfully we got things moving pretty smoothly about noon. I then proceeded to complete my first part of the Intro to Ruby curriculum! I now have a functioning CLI Tic Tac Toe game built in Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-004/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 04:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-004/</guid>
      <description>Today was no longer than the first few but definitely felt like it was. I learned the hard lesson that with this schedule I actually have to go to sleep when I schedule it. I stayed up late last night but still stuck to my 6 am wake-up call. Needless to say my last 30 minutes of coding tonight was not good and I couldn’t make progress like I know I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 04:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-003/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t think I need to announce what day it is anymore, lol. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve got my morning routine down now. Alarms go off at 6 am and I&amp;rsquo;m out of bed by 6:15 am typically. Coffee is done brewing by the time I get downstairs. Feed the dog and make my coffee (ghee is my only additive right now but I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to Bulletproof Coffee at some point using Brain Octane™ Oil).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 03:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-002/</guid>
      <description>Another day, more code. However, now I have the full bootcamp track! This is what I was waiting for: I also started tracking my time using Toggl solely because I was interested in exactly how long this bootcamp is going to take. Well, that and yesterday my wife asked me how much time I got to spend on school so now I&amp;rsquo;ll know. Started on some Ruby this morning and also learned that career placement starts when 75% of the curriculum is done (after Rails is complete).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 04:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-001/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 is finally upon me! I&amp;rsquo;ve got my setup ready as of last night after making a road trip to IKEA in Memphis, TN. After the price of gas I probably could have gotten a desk, chair, and that plastic thing you put on the floor for the same price here in Nashville but why not go to IKEA? I also know people are crazy for IKEA stuff so if we end up getting rid of this stuff someone will buy it quick!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before I Start Flatiron</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/before-i-start-flatiron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/before-i-start-flatiron/</guid>
      <description>There were a few things I had to get out of the way before I started Flatiron.
First, I needed a solid schedule I was going to follow. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to take 8 months to finish the program. In fact, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take 8 months to finish the program as my expenses were too much to stretch that long. I also wanted to minimize my family&amp;rsquo;s child care expenses so I came up with a solid schedule:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I? Why this blog?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a former hospitality professional working on a career transition by attending Flatiron&amp;rsquo;s online web development boot camp. I got tired of the required nights/weekends/holidays and 55+ hour work week as a salaried manager. I got tired of not seeing my children and making less than I felt my hard work was worth. So I decided to make a change. Web development had come easily to me and I had been teaching myself through free sources, mainly  Free Code Camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>home</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description>This is the home page&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>