<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily blog on My Flatiron Journey</title>
    <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/daily-blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Daily blog on My Flatiron Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/daily-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Makes Life Easier but Difficult</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-054/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 23:20:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-054/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuing with Rails. I now have 5 pages in my Cast Iron Design notebook. Something cool that I learned today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-erb&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- How link_to works --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;% @posts.each do |post| %&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;%= link_to post.title, post_path(post) %&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;!-- Creates the following HTML --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/posts/1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;My Title&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is pretty sweet considering how I was doing it in Sinatra. Something else that&amp;rsquo;s pretty sweet is that when we code &lt;code&gt;post_path(post)&lt;/code&gt; Rails is smart enough to know that it needs to use the id attribute of the &lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt; object we just passed in. No need to write &lt;code&gt;post.id&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Views in Rails also follow a convention of having a file extension of &lt;code&gt;.html.erb&lt;/code&gt; whereas in Sinatra I was only using &lt;code&gt;.erb&lt;/code&gt; for my views. Turns out Rails will render things right to left so first a file is having the embedded ruby rendered then it&amp;rsquo;s turned into html. It also appears that any plaintext will just be considered html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also been learning a ton about how routes are handles in Rails. It seemed a little counter intuitive compared to how I worked with Sinatra but as I keep learning and using it it is making much more sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m feeling stronger every day with in the future being able to pick up other frameworks based on the MVC structure. I&amp;rsquo;m getting a very low level instruction and understanding of how things work and I know I&amp;rsquo;ll be a better developer because of it. Even if it takes longer to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 2:20&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 204:44&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 4&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 420&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fog is in the Brain</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-053/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 22:44:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-053/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is tonight but I just can&amp;rsquo;t get into the groove. I&amp;rsquo;m steady distracted and not focused. And no it&amp;rsquo;s not because of the date, you know you were thinking it. Ugh. At least it&amp;rsquo;s on a &amp;ldquo;short&amp;rdquo; day and I did attend a meetup tonight so I did something beneficial to my coding journey that took a few hours of my evening. I am a few pages into one of my notebooks though so I can say that&amp;rsquo;s good. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll lookup the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/TR/cors/&#34;&gt;CORS&lt;/a&gt; spec instead of doing anymore Rails learning tonight. It&amp;rsquo;s a topic I heard about at the beginning of the month but still haven&amp;rsquo;t read up on at all (I had to look up that link just now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 1:11&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 202:24&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 4&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 416&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yay! You&#39;re on Rails!</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-052/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 23:22:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-052/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I started &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubyonrails.org/&#34;&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt; in all it&amp;rsquo;s glory. This will be my first full on framework that I get to work with. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen though it&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that has so much the key will be to stay focused on what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to have Rails do instead of everything it can do. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy to think that after this large section Career Services will be reaching out to me to start that process while I finished up the JS part of the program. I have 104 lessons, labs, and lectures left before 3 projects. My goal is to be doing Rails projects by May 10th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started taking some more organized notes in my little notebook. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that works out as we move forward. From looking over the curriculum authentication is the largest part of Rails so I&amp;rsquo;ll keep some good notes there. If I can keep myself from having to rewatch lecture videos I think the extra time writing things down will pay off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a software note. My favorite email client just had an upgrade and is available on Windows, Mac, and Linus now. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://nylas.com/nylas-mail/&#34;&gt;Nylas Mail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 3:00&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 201:13&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 6&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 412&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Deployed My Sinatra App To Heroku</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 23:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MY SINATRA PORTFOLIO PROJECT IS DONE!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can say I&amp;rsquo;m pretty stoked. This blog is part of the requirements though so get ready :-). Actually, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take enough notes to really get into the code in this blog. I did hit some solid stumbling blocks and there is some major refactoring of code needing to happen but I&amp;rsquo;m overall pretty happy. A large part of the time I spent was making the app look good utilizing &lt;a href=&#34;https://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that definitely needs to be refactored is one of my helper methods:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;def current_user_parents
  parents = []
  current_user(session).houses.each do |house|
    Parent.where(house_id: house.id).each do |parent|
      parents &amp;lt;&amp;lt; parent
    end
  end
  parents
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s sandwich code (starts with a variable set to an empty array, fills that array, returns that array) so I know I can most likely eliminate two lines from that or even three if I&amp;rsquo;m not pushing onto that &lt;code&gt;parents&lt;/code&gt; variable anymore. We&amp;rsquo;ll see. I&amp;rsquo;m interested to pick the brain of the instructor that goes over the project with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see what I&amp;rsquo;ll call v0.8 (I figure it&amp;rsquo;s close to v1.0 but not yet lol) at &lt;a href=&#34;https://your-neighbors.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;https://your-neighbors.herokuapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;. I feel like the code is solid but still some functionality and visual things that need to be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to add a static footer to the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a house is deleted the parent and children remain in the database but can never be accessed again because of how I list them in relation to the house they&amp;rsquo;re in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When there are no parents or children I need to add a link suggesting to create some.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user tries to access the info for something they didn&amp;rsquo;t create (ie. they created house 8 but try and go to the link for house 5) the error page tells them to login even though they are logged in. I need to create a different error page for logged in users trying to access stuff that isn&amp;rsquo;t there&amp;rsquo;s vs. the error page when a person isn&amp;rsquo;t logged in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some color!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure I could find more. Feel free to check out the app. Sign up, use it, and report issues to the GitHub link at the top right on every page of the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting deploying to Heroku as well. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a solid guide on deploying a Sinatra app with a DB to Heroku. Through Heroku&amp;rsquo;s docs and this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sitepoint.com/get-started-with-sinatra-on-heroku/&#34;&gt;Get Started with Sinatra on Heroku&lt;/a&gt; from 2013 I got it up and running though. The biggest thing was setting up Postgres and what to put in the &lt;code&gt;Procfile&lt;/code&gt;. Let me see if I can remember what exactly I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;gem &#39;pg&#39;&lt;/code&gt; to your Gemfile. Also, define your version of ruby, ie. &lt;code&gt;ruby &#39;2.4.1&#39;&lt;/code&gt; in your Gemfile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I changed the sqlite gem to development like this &lt;code&gt;gem &#39;sqlite3&#39;, :group =&amp;gt; :development&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I added a &lt;code&gt;config/database.yml&lt;/code&gt; because the Heroku docs said to but I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s needed. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably delete it and see what happens in the near future. The Heroku docs have an example that I used and just changed the &lt;code&gt;database:&lt;/code&gt; names.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;config/environment.rb&lt;/code&gt; is where the magic happened. I kept the &lt;code&gt;:development&lt;/code&gt; environment using sqlite3 because I read in some of the docs that you needed to know the host, username, password, port and something else to make it work locally. I figured if I could get it to work without figuring that out I would do that. I got this working locally running &lt;code&gt;shotgun&lt;/code&gt; and on the Heroku server too. With the changes it now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;require &#39;bundler/setup&#39;
Bundler.require

configure :development do
  ENV[&#39;SINATRA_ENV&#39;] ||= &amp;quot;development&amp;quot;

  ActiveRecord::Base.establish_connection(
    :adapter =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;sqlite3&amp;quot;,
    :database =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;db/neighborhood#{ENV[&#39;SINATRA_ENV&#39;]}.sqlite&amp;quot;
  )
end

configure :production do
  db = URI.parse(ENV[&#39;DATABASE_URL&#39;] || &#39;postgres://localhost/mydb&#39;)

  ActiveRecord::Base.establish_connection(
    :adapter =&amp;gt; db.scheme == &#39;postgres&#39; ? &#39;postgresql&#39; : db.scheme,
    :host     =&amp;gt; db.host,
    :username =&amp;gt; db.user,
    :password =&amp;gt; db.password,
    :database =&amp;gt; db.path[1..-1],
    :encoding =&amp;gt; &#39;utf8&#39;
  )
end

require_all &#39;app&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Procfile&lt;/code&gt; was something I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sitepoint.com/&#34;&gt;SitePoint&lt;/a&gt; article I linked above had this line for it and this is what made it all work &lt;code&gt;web: bundle exec rackup config.ru -p $PORT&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the rest I followed the Ruby docs on Heroku &lt;a href=&#34;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/getting-started-with-ruby#introduction&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the SQLite doc &lt;a href=&#34;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/sqlite3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you get db migration errors you can run rake tasks on Heroku. &lt;code&gt;heroku run rake db:migrate&lt;/code&gt; was one that I needed to do. More in dept docs about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/rake&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, look at that. I remembered way more than I thought. Hopefully this was helpful to someone somewhere. Probably a student coming behind me who is going to pull their hair out trying to get their app to work on Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 8:32&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 198:13&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 1&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 406&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you Gifted?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-050/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 23:19:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-050/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not much to report today. I got some free passes from being a member of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.us.mensa.org/&#34;&gt;American Mensa&lt;/a&gt; to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foxsearchlight.com/gifted/&#34;&gt;Gifted&lt;/a&gt;. So the wife and I went to see that tonight. It&amp;rsquo;s a good movie and I recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished up the controller and views for one part of my Sinatra project. It&amp;rsquo;s coming along nicely. Now that I have this done I don&amp;rsquo;t think the next two controllers and associated views will take as long. It should be pretty close to the same thing just modifying some small amounts of code. I am still deciding between radio buttons and a dropdown for some of my &lt;code&gt;create&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;update&lt;/code&gt; forms. Parents will only be allowed to be associated with one house so deciding how to visually represent that. I think the dropdown will work better only because this app could potentially have a lot of entries in it. I also need to code in that when a House is deleted so are the members of the house. However, I&amp;rsquo;ll work on that once I actually have associated members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 1:00&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 189:40&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 0&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 405&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Easter</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-049/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 22:05:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-049/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to take the weekend off and enjoy the Easter holiday with the family. I had been going hard for almost 7 straight weeks. Back at it tomorrow. I also ordered my Code &amp;amp; Quill Origin this weekend. Looking forward to getting my notebooks just in time to take notes on Rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 0:00&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 188:40&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 0&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 405&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It Look nice</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-047/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 23:07:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-047/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So about that not being fancy that I talked about last night. I took a good chunk of time today and figured out how to implement &lt;a href=&#34;https://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; in my portfolio project. I figured this was my first web app and should probably look somewhat nice. I have a navbar that changes if you&amp;rsquo;re logged in or not and then I&amp;rsquo;m using the form and typography stylings. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely taking me longer to write my forms out and I&amp;rsquo;m making sure my app actually will look good so that is taking more time as well. However, I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to be more proud of this when I&amp;rsquo;m done. You can follow my progress on my project &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/itzsaga/neighbor_tracker&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Although, that link might break in the future as I&amp;rsquo;ll probably renanme my repo to something less stalkerish lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to get my naming correct for my &lt;code&gt;has_many&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;has_many&lt;/code&gt; relationship. Between the models and the db it was a mistake in what needed to be plural that ultimately took some time to figure out. I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep up with these associations in any complex manner. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why but I&amp;rsquo;m exhausted right now. I&amp;rsquo;m usually still humming along at 11:15pm but not tonight. I&amp;rsquo;m fighting to stay awake. I made some great progress today on my Sinatra project and I&amp;rsquo;m happy with where I&amp;rsquo;m at. I could&amp;rsquo;ve been closer to being done but I know that I&amp;rsquo;ll be more proud to show off my project because of how it looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 6:20&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 188:40&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 0&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 405&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crushing Fwitter Tonight was Sweet</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-046/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 23:44:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s late so I&amp;rsquo;ll be brief. I crushed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/itzsaga/sinatra-fwitter-group-project-v-000&#34;&gt;my project&lt;/a&gt; tonight and I&amp;rsquo;m ready to start my Sinatra portfolio project tomorrow. I think I can have an ugly version (desktown down design, raw forms, no nav bar or footer) done tomorrow at some point and then leave it alone until after my project review with an instructor. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes. The requirements are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build an MVC Sinatra Application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use ActiveRecord with Sinatra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Multiple Models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use at least one &lt;code&gt;has_many&lt;/code&gt; relationship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must have user accounts. The user that created a given piece of content should be the only person who can modify that content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should validate user input to ensure that bad data isn&amp;rsquo;t created&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it might be ambitious to think I can finish that in a day or two but I&amp;rsquo;m confident I can with what I have planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to utilize Active Record Validations tonight. I also included HTML5 &lt;code&gt;required&lt;/code&gt; tags in my forms. However, the tests were sending raw params data to the post route so it was bypassing utilizing my forms to test. I guess this is good though because it creates a situation where if someone sends bad data to the server through a method other than the server it&amp;rsquo;ll reject it. However, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want the server hit every time a bad form is input. Maybe a combo of the two makes sense? That way data is validated in the browser and when being saved to the server. Here&amp;rsquo;s what an Active Record Validation looks like from &lt;a href=&#34;http://guides.rubyonrails.org/active_record_validations.html&#34;&gt;Rails Guides&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;class Person &amp;lt; ApplicationRecord
  validates :name, presence: true
end
 
Person.create(name: &amp;quot;John Doe&amp;quot;).valid? # =&amp;gt; true
Person.create(name: nil).valid? # =&amp;gt; false
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also decided to buy the &lt;a href=&#34;http://castirondesign.com/work/eco-pocket-sized-notebook&#34;&gt;Cast Iron Design Eco Pocket-Sized Notebook&lt;/a&gt; pack of 3 to start. I realized that AMEX is offering a bonus if you redeem points towards purchases until the end of the month. While redemption values are almost always lowest when using AMEX points for bill credits with the 20% bump it&amp;rsquo;s worth using for a few small things. Considering we have 70k of them $12 won&amp;rsquo;t make a dent in that. I still plan to get a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codeandquill.com/collections/notebooks/products/origin&#34;&gt;Code &amp;amp; Quill Origin&lt;/a&gt; when they&amp;rsquo;re not sold out anymore. The fact that there are spacing markers that will make written code look good is sweet (not like you can&amp;rsquo;t do that on graph paper but still).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think one of the biggest things I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing that has helped me not get bogged down as I&amp;rsquo;m moving through the curriculum and projects is to not get too fancy. I&amp;rsquo;m also not overthinking it. I&amp;rsquo;m being very straightforward in what I&amp;rsquo;m putting together and making things that work. Could pretty much everything be &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;? Yes. However, I&amp;rsquo;m looking to have a body of work to present. I honestly feel that when it comes job hiring time the strength of the code will outweigh the shiny UI&amp;rsquo;s. I still plan on going back and polishing everything up and making it look nice (or at least nicer) than the project requirements require.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 3:13&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 182:20&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 1&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 405&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing it Down Always Helps</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-045/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 23:10:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-045/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking it easy tonight. I have to get some work done for &lt;a href=&#34;http://giftofadoption.org/&#34;&gt;Gift of Adoption Fund&lt;/a&gt;, the non-profit I volunteer on the board for here in TN. Shameless plug, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/GiftofAdoptionTennessee/&#34;&gt;Like our Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt; please. I finished up the NYC lab in &amp;lt;30 minutes. The second controller and views were much more simple. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to refactor my code yet. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t think a helper methods are needed as I didn&amp;rsquo;t use that code anywhere in my other controller. Maybe though, maybe. I watched the two lecture videos and finished my DB migrations and building out the models on my first Sinatra project as well tonight. I still go back and forth with feeling like I&amp;rsquo;m getting enough accomplished each day but hitting milestones and goals (even if 3 days late) feels good. My wife is off Friday so hopefully that&amp;rsquo;ll allow me some good time to get work done since we have a birthday party Saturday and it&amp;rsquo;s Easter on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another note, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out a notebook to buy. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Moleskine&amp;rsquo;s in the past. Nothing against them but not what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for right now. Field Notes seem expensive for what they are and you&amp;rsquo;re paying for the cool factor more than the notebook. So, I did some research. Deciding between the &lt;a href=&#34;http://castirondesign.com/work/eco-pocket-sized-notebook&#34;&gt;Cast Iron Design Eco Pocket-Sized Notebook&lt;/a&gt;, any of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codeandquill.com/collections/notebooks&#34;&gt;Code &amp;amp; Quill&lt;/a&gt; books although at this price I&amp;rsquo;d go hardcover, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wordnotebooks.com/products/word-notebooks-dot-grid&#34;&gt;Word. Dot Grid&lt;/a&gt; because it&amp;rsquo;s Field Notes but not, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.muji.us/store/recycled-paper-bind-notebook-grid-30-sheets-a5-dark-gray4548076398349.html&#34;&gt;MUJI Recycled Paper Bing Notebook A5&lt;/a&gt; because they&amp;rsquo;re dirt cheap. Let me know what you think. I&amp;rsquo;m leaning towards Code &amp;amp; Quill most likely. I think the larger hardcover books will be benneficial to have segmented by language and framework. I can create personal reference libraries in them and add as time goes on. I can have a master Ruby book, a JS book, a Rails book, is the thought at least. Or maybe I start with smaller books and if a top turns in to two books it gets a C&amp;amp;Q book and I transcribe over what I already have which wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be much at that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 1:50&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 179:08&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 3&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 404&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helper Methods Tested, How to Not Repeat Yourself</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-044/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 23:16:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-044/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m on a killer roll right now blowing through this NYC lab. Built my 3 tables and 1 &lt;code&gt;JOIN&lt;/code&gt; table migrations. Built out the associated models. Built out all the views and one controller. Have one controller and it&amp;rsquo;s views left now. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t have kids that were going to wake me up between 6:30am and 8:00am I&amp;rsquo;d finish it up. I think it&amp;rsquo;ll take me maybe 30 more mins (mostly because &lt;strong&gt;A LOT&lt;/strong&gt; of it is going to be similar to the controller &amp;amp; views I just built) but sleep is needed. I also need to finish doing my part of the household chores (dishes tonight) before bed so in the interest of rest I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty hype and think I&amp;rsquo;ll still be on schedule to finish the review videos tomorrow night. I also feel more confident about attacking the portfolio project. The only part I haven&amp;rsquo;t really dug into is the UI. I figure a basic bootstrap will do. Utilize the &lt;code&gt;layout.erb&lt;/code&gt; to have a consistent header and footer and I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy at this point in time (when that time comes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m contemplating creating helper methods for my controllers. Currently the one controller I finished tonight (I&amp;rsquo;ll do the other and all it&amp;rsquo;s views tomorrow) is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;class FiguresController &amp;lt; ApplicationController

  get &#39;/figures&#39; do
    @figures = Figure.all
    erb :&#39;figures/index&#39;
  end

  get &#39;/figures/new&#39; do
    @figures = Figure.all
    @landmarks = Landmark.all
    @titles = Title.all
    erb :&#39;figures/new&#39;
  end

  get &#39;/figures/:id&#39; do
    @figure = Figure.find(params[:id])
    erb :&#39;figures/show&#39;
  end

  post &#39;/figures/:id&#39; do
    @figure = Figure.find(params[:id])
    @figure.update(params[:figure])

    if !params[:title][:name].empty?
      if !!params[:figure][:title_ids]
        params[:figure][:title_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Title.create(params[:title]).id
      else
        params[:figure][:title_ids] = []
        params[:figure][:title_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Title.create(params[:title]).id
      end
    end
    @figure.title_ids = params[:figure][:title_ids]

    if !params[:landmark][:name].empty?
      if !!params[:figure][:landmark_ids]
        params[:figure][:landmark_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Landmark.create(params[:landmark]).id
      else
        params[:figure][:landmark_ids] = []
        params[:figure][:landmark_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Landmark.create(params[:landmark]).id
      end
    end
    @figure.landmark_ids = params[:figure][:landmark_ids]

    @figure.save

    redirect to &amp;quot;/figures/#{@figure.id}&amp;quot;
  end

  get &#39;/figures/:id/edit&#39; do
    @figure = Figure.find(params[:id])
    @landmarks = Landmark.all
    @titles = Title.all
    erb :&#39;figures/edit&#39;
  end

  post &#39;/figures&#39; do
    @figure = Figure.create(params[:figure])

    if !params[:title][:name].empty?
      if !!params[:figure][:title_ids]
        params[:figure][:title_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Title.create(params[:title]).id
      else
        params[:figure][:title_ids] = []
        params[:figure][:title_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Title.create(params[:title]).id
      end
    end
    @figure.title_ids = params[:figure][:title_ids]

    if !params[:landmark][:name].empty?
      if !!params[:figure][:landmark_ids]
        params[:figure][:landmark_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Landmark.create(params[:landmark]).id
      else
        params[:figure][:landmark_ids] = []
        params[:figure][:landmark_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Landmark.create(params[:landmark]).id
      end
    end
    @figure.landmark_ids = params[:figure][:landmark_ids]

    @figure.save

    redirect to &amp;quot;/figures/#{@figure.id}&amp;quot;
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main parts thar violate DRY (don&amp;rsquo;t repeat yourself) should be readily evident in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;if !params[:title][:name].empty?
  if !!params[:figure][:title_ids]
    params[:figure][:title_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Title.create(params[:title]).id
  else
    params[:figure][:title_ids] = []
    params[:figure][:title_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Title.create(params[:title]).id
  end
end
@figure.title_ids = params[:figure][:title_ids]

if !params[:landmark][:name].empty?
  if !!params[:figure][:landmark_ids]
    params[:figure][:landmark_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Landmark.create(params[:landmark]).id
  else
    params[:figure][:landmark_ids] = []
    params[:figure][:landmark_ids] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Landmark.create(params[:landmark]).id
  end
end
@figure.landmark_ids = params[:figure][:landmark_ids]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only are these lines with a nested &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; statement not elegant but they are carbon copies of each other. In addition, I forsee using almost the same exact methods in my other controller. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have one of these &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; blocks utilizing &lt;code&gt;figure_ids&lt;/code&gt; but other than that it&amp;rsquo;ll be pretty close. We&amp;rsquo;ll see and if that&amp;rsquo;s true I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely create 3 helper methods and just use those if I can. It&amp;rsquo;ll be good practice in building helper methods for the controller because I haven&amp;rsquo;t done that before. I&amp;rsquo;ve built a module for the models in my last lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A note I took that didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense at the time was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define helper methods in the Application Controller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After tonight I see exactly why. This is because the individual controllers (at least in my case) are inherting from the app controller. I was thinking initially I would have to create a &lt;code&gt;Helper&lt;/code&gt; class of some sort and then utilize them that way but I have this basically empty file that the controllers are already using so it makes sense to put helper methods right in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 2:09&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 177:17&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 0&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 401&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Playlister with Quick Superior Code</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-043/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 23:29:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-043/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got a large lab done tonight. Right on schedule. I was done 2 minutes after 11pm. I basically took the Music Library CLI app that I made earlier in the curriculum and turned it into a much more user friendly Sinatra MVC web app. The final code can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/itzsaga/playlister-sinatra-v-000&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The biggest challenge I had was setting up my databases and models. Actually, just with the &lt;code&gt;JOIN&lt;/code&gt; table. However, I know the more I do this the easier it will get. It&amp;rsquo;s still &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; new and a complex thing to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also attended a study group this afternoon and saw another student&amp;rsquo;s Sinatra portfolio project he was working on. After quickly glancing at the project info, this line gave me an idea for my project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app should be a custom app that is created to track something important to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my family just moved into a new neighborhood in January I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping track of who our neighbors are in an EverNote Doc. Pretty much, address, matriarch, patriarch and kids with ages. I figured I could have 3 tables in this app. One for the House with an address. Then the House &lt;code&gt;has_many&lt;/code&gt; Parents and &lt;code&gt;has_many&lt;/code&gt; Kids through Parents. Parents with Name and Phone Number values. Parents will &lt;code&gt;belongs_to&lt;/code&gt; a House and &lt;code&gt;has_many&lt;/code&gt; Kids. Kids will have name, age, and sex fields (for those unisex names). Kids will &lt;code&gt;has_many&lt;/code&gt; Parents and &lt;code&gt;belongs_to&lt;/code&gt; a House through Parents. I told my instructor this briefly during the study group and he said that was more than enough to fulfill the requirements of the project. All the project requires is a single &lt;code&gt;has_many&lt;/code&gt; relationship in terms of the database aspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also asked about if there was a preference between &lt;a href=&#34;http://guides.rubyonrails.org/active_record_validations.html&#34;&gt;Active Record Validations&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/HTML/Forms/Form_validation&#34;&gt;HTML5 Form Validations&lt;/a&gt;. He said HTML5 form validations were further in the curriculum so most would not be using them at this point in time. However, it&amp;rsquo;s just use case choice. Of course, HTML5 form validations won&amp;rsquo;t hit the DB so there&amp;rsquo;s that as well he said. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how complex HTML5 form validation was until I looked it up (see the link at the beginning of this paragraph) and now I realize why it isn&amp;rsquo;t taught until later. I was thinking of simple input contraints like those found &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/input&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Now there are some things that must hit the server to validate. For example, if you wanted to ensure an email address hadn&amp;rsquo;t been registered already there is only one way to check that. This is where something like Active Record&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://guides.rubyonrails.org/active_record_validations.html#uniqueness&#34;&gt;uniqueness helper&lt;/a&gt; comes into play. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how far down this rabbit hole I&amp;rsquo;ll go building out my project. Maybe just a simple &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;type=&amp;quot;tel&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in what I was thinking of above. Although, since this is a portfolio project I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure to keep a set of features I want to implement to improve the app. I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure to work on getting these things done when the job hunt starts. Currently the goal is to get to that point as quickly as possible so I&amp;rsquo;m completing projects with close to the bare minimum requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 3:16&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 175:09&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 1&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 401&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching Through Roadblocks Quickly is Monumental Now</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-042/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 23:22:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-042/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was the day of road blocks. I spent probably 3 hours working with Learn Experts on problems. For the most part these were dev environment issues or weird test issues and not working through my code and learning new things. I did learn some things about debugging though. I learned to check my Gemfile because if a gem is missing weird things happen. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how I was able to run &lt;code&gt;shotgun&lt;/code&gt; without having the gem in the Gemfile but it worked and then I got odd errors in my browser. Easy fix once it was figured out but that took an hour. I also learned that when doing TDD work on each test as you go rather than the entire thing. I had two forms that were very similar so I copied and pasted the first into the code for the second. I made all the edits I thought I needed to and then ran the tests. I kept getting an odd error saying an element wasn&amp;rsquo;t there but I knew it was. Turns out code further down in my form was breaking my entire view and thus Capybara was unable to read the entire page. If it can&amp;rsquo;t read the page at all of course the element will be missing. So I commented out the rest of the code and worked test by test after that and had much more success. However, figuring this out took another hour tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this time having others review my code let me beat my brother in a game of chess :-). If you want to play me you can find me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chess.com/&#34;&gt;Chess.com&lt;/a&gt; at my profile &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chess.com/member/itzsaga&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned more about databases and how I&amp;rsquo;ll utilize them with ActiveRecord in my Sinatra apps. Specifically I know that the JOIN table will come up again in the future. As this is one of the more confusing topics I made sure to save this overview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A join table is a table that only has two columns. To keep up with the online store example, this table would contain a &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;item_id&lt;/code&gt;. Each row in this table would contain a user&amp;rsquo;s ID and an item&amp;rsquo;s ID. We call this join table &lt;code&gt;user_items&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;has_many :through&lt;/code&gt; is always singular and in the first part of the join table name, and the &lt;code&gt;belongs_to&lt;/code&gt; portion of the relationship is pluralized in the second part of the table name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m 2 labs and 2 lectures behind my goal :-(. New goal is to be done with these 4 things by Wednesday night. I think I can finish each lab in a 3 hour sitting so that&amp;rsquo;s Monday and Tuesday night then watch the lectures on Wednesday. I looked and I&amp;rsquo;m about 10 hours behind the amount of time I wanted to code this week and that&amp;rsquo;s basically what I missed it by. I need to reup on my strict adherence to my schedule. While I&amp;rsquo;m moving along I could be further along than I am and closer to being employed at this point in time. I&amp;rsquo;m dreading the feeling I&amp;rsquo;ll have if I make that one extra tuition payment when I know it could&amp;rsquo;ve been avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 6:47&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 171:53&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 8&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 400&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I suddenly know how it all fits together better.</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-041/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 23:21:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-041/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I moved through a lot of curriculum today. However, I really want to hit the goal I set two weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m on the cusp of it! I had 21 lessons/labs to go for my goal when I checked early in the day. So I set a goal of 11 more today (I had laready finished 2) and finish tomorrow. I missed it by one only because it&amp;rsquo;s late and I hit an hour and a half review lecture. Since I&amp;rsquo;m working on ActiveRecord sessions and authentication I want to pay better attention to this lecture than I usually do. Maybe even take a note or two :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ealy in the day I got stuck on a nested forms lab. I was getting an error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Failures:
  1) App POST /teams submits the form
     Failure/Error: click_button &#39;submit&#39;
     TypeError:
       expected Hash (got String) for param `name&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why. My code was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Create a Team and Heroes!&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;form action=&amp;quot;/teams&amp;quot; method=&amp;quot;POST&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Team Name: &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Team Motto: &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[motto]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Hero 1&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Name: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member1_name&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name][hero][][name]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Power: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member1_power&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name][hero][][power]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Biography: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member1_bio&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name][hero][][bio]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Hero 2&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Name: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member2_name&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name][hero][][name]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Power: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member2_power&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name][hero][][power]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Biography: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member2_bio&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name][hero][][bio]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Hero 3&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Name: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member3_name&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name][hero][][name]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Power: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member3_power&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name][hero][][power]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Biography: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member3_bio&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name][hero][][bio]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;button type=&amp;quot;submit&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;submit&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Submit&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept thinking, &amp;ldquo;How can form input be anything other than a String? Why is it expecting a hash?&amp;rdquo; I reached out to a Learn Expert (they&amp;rsquo;re like Teaching Assistants who are available almost &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; to help) and it took almost an hour to resolve it. However, figured out that because my third line had &lt;code&gt;name=&amp;quot;team[name]&lt;/code&gt; whenever I called a nested hash that contained &lt;code&gt;team[name]&lt;/code&gt; it was returning the string I input instead of setting the params nested hash array to the proper thing. A quick change of my code to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Create a Team and Heroes!&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;form action=&amp;quot;/teams&amp;quot; method=&amp;quot;POST&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Team Name: &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[name]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Team Motto: &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[motto]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Hero 1&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Name: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member1_name&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[hero][][name]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Power: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member1_power&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[hero][][power]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Biography: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member1_bio&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[hero][][bio]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Hero 2&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Name: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member2_name&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[hero][][name]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Power: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member2_power&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[hero][][power]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Biography: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member2_bio&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[hero][][bio]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Hero 3&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Name: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member3_name&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[hero][][name]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Power: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member3_power&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[hero][][power]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Hero&#39;s Biography: &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;member3_bio&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;team[hero][][bio]&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;button type=&amp;quot;submit&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;submit&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Submit&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and my tests were all passing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized today that I&amp;rsquo;ve been achieving the end goal of clearing out hashes without using the method provided by ruby. When I read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily for us, there is already a Ruby method for emptying a hash: #clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought to myself, &amp;ldquo;Whoops!&amp;rdquo; because I&amp;rsquo;ve just been resetting hashes &amp;amp; arrays by doing &lt;code&gt;@session = {}&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;@@all = []&lt;/code&gt; up until this point. I haven&amp;rsquo;t checked the docs yet to make sure this method applies to arrays as well but I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it used so I&amp;rsquo;m relatively confident in that. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll find out the first time I use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 6:37&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 165:06&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 12&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 392&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do recruiters make you mad? What&#39;s your advice?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-040/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 23:02:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-040/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So nested forms aren&amp;rsquo;t as bad as I thought they would be. I guess it helps that I had some good teaching before I got into it. I think I had the longest video yet to watch tonight and that took up most of the time once I finished the lab I started last night. The lab I&amp;rsquo;m on seems to be more of the same just getting the concept to stick with a more in depth nested form. It has an option to persist the data &lt;strong&gt;AFTER&lt;/strong&gt; getting the tests to pass initially. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll attempt it or not. I know I&amp;rsquo;ll need to know the skill but does it help me more to struggle now and be a little quicker later? Or just struggle later one time? I know doing it more is definitely better but there are concessions I make in the interest of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learned a good workflow for building a MVC app that uses a databse. First start with the DB, then work on models, then controller routes, and finally the views. I had thought working in the other direction would make more sense but I&amp;rsquo;ll try what the lecture taught. My thinking is, I start with a view so I know what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to display, I&amp;rsquo;ll have my endpoint even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll build the route that will fill in that view. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll build the model for the controller to use. Then build the database knowing the full amount of things I&amp;rsquo;ll need. This is how I thought I did the CLI Gem project where I started with the lowest level and worked my way out with stubbed data to get a final point where when I had real data it just worked. This might not be the best workflow when dealing with things like databases and controllers though. There might be things outside of my control that could end up creating a whole rewrite which would be very sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put in a resume for a Jr. Dev (or was it Jr. Analyst?) role today and the recruiter called me back. To my surprise saying they work with a few companies that take bootcamp grads. The main thing I was told is to finish and get that official certification or diploma saying I finished then we could talk. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to already be connected with someone even if it turns out to be nothing. While I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with recruiters in the past and never received an offer through any assistance they&amp;rsquo;ve given I think any interview is a good one for me moving into a new field. The questions and format will be something completely different from what I&amp;rsquo;m used to. As much as we all wish interviews could be nailed by the best candidate every time they just aren&amp;rsquo;t and interviewing is a skill in and of itself. I&amp;rsquo;m interested if there are any others out there that have used recruiters to land Junior level positions and what they thought about the process in hindsight?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 2:44&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 158:29&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 2&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 380&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Take it Easy Sometimes and Still Win</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-039/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 22:29:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-039/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I only got a little bit of coding done tonight by choice. I think I&amp;rsquo;m procrastinating on this nested hash forms lab because nested hashes can get confusing. I started it though and just got sidetracked. I need to stay focused. I worked on getting &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/ruby/&#34;&gt;RubyMine&lt;/a&gt; installed to see what it&amp;rsquo;s about and my computer froze. After that I just gave up on coding tonight. I guess I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very motivated if that&amp;rsquo;s all it took lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I went to a good Ruby meetup tonight and got home late and am just distracted. I went to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/nashrb/&#34;&gt;Nash.rb&lt;/a&gt; 2nd Quarter Social tonight and hung out with people that are in the Ruby community here in Nashville. It was laid back and I just spoke with a bunch of people. A guy named Sam who just moved to Nashville last month and has 3 years of Rails experience yet went to Law school. Chris who graduated from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theironyard.com/locations/nashville.html&#34;&gt;The Iron Yard&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Front End program in December and is just interested in Ruby. Pete who&amp;rsquo;s a VP at &lt;a href=&#34;https://takl.com/&#34;&gt;Takl&lt;/a&gt; who are looking for a Senior RoR&amp;rsquo;s dev. Jon and Jim who are both 10+ year devs who talked about their company but never named it. I was able to look at the Meetup RSVP list and then check LinkedIn to see they work for &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups360.com/&#34;&gt;Groups360&lt;/a&gt;. Their company interested me because they&amp;rsquo;re looking to provide a SaaS product to the hospitality industry. Ty who works for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kindful.com/&#34;&gt;Kindful&lt;/a&gt; and is somewhat jealous that he had to get a CS degree (75% of which was useless he said) because boot camps didn&amp;rsquo;t exist when he started. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s the nootropics I&amp;rsquo;m taking or if I consciously made sure of it but I remembered every person&amp;rsquo;s name I met tonight and was able to say goodnight to them by name as well. This typically doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this meetup to be much more interesting to me than the previous ones I have attended. I think it&amp;rsquo;s because we were interacting well and I was able to speak with all different levels of people. I&amp;rsquo;ve found there is &lt;strong&gt;A LOT&lt;/strong&gt; of JavaScript around, and for good reason, so it as nice to speak to people who knew the things I&amp;rsquo;m currently learning. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the Nash.rb meetups in the future. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to enjoying JS meetups as well as soon as I get to the JS curriculum and get back to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 0:33&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 155:45&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 0&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 378&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>