<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on My Flatiron Journey</title>
    <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/general/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on My Flatiron Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Before I Start Flatiron</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/before-i-start-flatiron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/before-i-start-flatiron/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There were a few things I had to get out of the way before I started Flatiron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I needed a solid schedule I was going to follow. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to take 8 months to finish the program. In fact, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take 8 months to finish the program as my expenses were too much to stretch that long. I also wanted to minimize my family&amp;rsquo;s child care expenses so I came up with a solid schedule:&lt;br /&gt;
M-Th 6am-7am personal care (shower, breakfast, walk dog, etc&amp;hellip;) 7am-8am (or whenever kids wake up) Flatiron. 8am-8pm family/kids. 8pm-10pm Flatiron. 3 hrs/day.&lt;br /&gt;
Fri-Sun 8am-10pm Flatiron (1 hour lunch &amp;amp; dinner). 12 hrs/day.&lt;br /&gt;
Total 53 hours of school per week.&lt;br /&gt;
~800 hours to graduation = 15 weeks.&lt;br /&gt;
This seemed doable as my former career in restaurant management had me working 55 hours standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I needed somewhere to do this work. The house we had just built had a closed in office which was not in use. So I skimmed IKEA&amp;rsquo;s website and picked out a desk and chair. Granted IKEA is 3 hours away from my house so it will be a pain to go pick it up but spending $100 on a desk, chair, and that plastic thing you put on the carpet so a chair can roll seemed like it was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the plan was coming together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>