<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flatiron blog on My Flatiron Journey</title>
    <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/flatiron-blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flatiron blog on My Flatiron Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 23:34:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/flatiron-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I Deployed My Sinatra App To Heroku</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 23:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</guid>
      <description>MY SINATRA PORTFOLIO PROJECT IS DONE!!!
You can say I&amp;rsquo;m pretty stoked. This blog is part of the requirements though so get ready :-). Actually, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take enough notes to really get into the code in this blog. I did hit some solid stumbling blocks and there is some major refactoring of code needing to happen but I&amp;rsquo;m overall pretty happy. A large part of the time I spent was making the app look good utilizing Bootstrap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Way To Pair Program</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/one-way-to-pair-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 23:07:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/one-way-to-pair-program/</guid>
      <description>Tonight a couple people were wanting to know the best way to pair program together. They had both done the beginning parts of the Tic-Tac-Toe with AI project (the one I&amp;rsquo;m getting ready to start) and wanted to work on the AI part together. The exact question was:
 Hey @*** and I are doing parallel pairing :slightly_smiling_face: what is the best way to go about this, to work on the same repo on separate branches or just copy on paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Software Development?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/why-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 19:40:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/why-software-development/</guid>
      <description>So as part of my bootcamp experience Flatiron School requires me to write blog posts. This is a feature that I don&amp;rsquo;t think all bootcamps have but is smart. If I can write about coding then I show a deeper understanding about why I am a job ready developer. We all know that our online presence is part of our &amp;ldquo;resume&amp;rdquo; now as more and more hiring managers are looking at social profiles when making job decisions (even if it&amp;rsquo;s a [legal slippery slope&amp;hellip;][1]).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>