<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flatiron blog on My Flatiron Journey</title>
    <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/flatiron-blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flatiron blog on My Flatiron Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 15:22:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/flatiron-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project Complete...</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/so-close-to-the-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 15:22:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/so-close-to-the-end/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been about 3 weeks since I last blogged. I put my head down and sprinted towards the finish line. I can&amp;rsquo;t say that I&amp;rsquo;m 100% done, yet, but I will be soon. I have completed my final portfolio project and have my assessment for it tomorrow. I must say, Redux threw me for one while working on this project. I hit many stumbling blocks building this project. I think my sprint was alittle ambitious and I ended up not knowing the Redux stuff as in depth as I wanted to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes The Logic Is Flawed</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/sometimes-the-logic-is-flawed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 23:01:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/sometimes-the-logic-is-flawed/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;m banging away at my jQuery project. I got hung up on some code tonight but got it working right before I stopped for the night! I was stoked! So what was I stuck on? In my app a user can create as many places as they want. Each place can have as many items as they want. A user can look at a specific item and see the name of it, the rating they gave it, any notes they wrote about it and where the item is available (the places they&amp;rsquo;ve added it to).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did I Really Finish Rails?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/did-i-really-finish-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 18:45:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/did-i-really-finish-rails/</guid>
      <description>My Rails project is officially done! Well, it officially fulfills all the requirements that Flatiron School has for it. I definitely have more to do with it. However, considering that I&amp;rsquo;m done almost a day and a half before my self set deadline I&amp;rsquo;m happy. Some minor things in my views (like showing just a user&amp;rsquo;s items instead of all items), building out a more robust navbar, filling out my readme, and I should be good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Deployed My Sinatra App To Heroku</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 23:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</guid>
      <description>MY SINATRA PORTFOLIO PROJECT IS DONE!!!
You can say I&amp;rsquo;m pretty stoked. This blog is part of the requirements though so get ready :-). Actually, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take enough notes to really get into the code in this blog. I did hit some solid stumbling blocks and there is some major refactoring of code needing to happen but I&amp;rsquo;m overall pretty happy. A large part of the time I spent was making the app look good utilizing Bootstrap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Way To Pair Program</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/one-way-to-pair-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 23:07:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/one-way-to-pair-program/</guid>
      <description>Tonight a couple people were wanting to know the best way to pair program together. They had both done the beginning parts of the Tic-Tac-Toe with AI project (the one I&amp;rsquo;m getting ready to start) and wanted to work on the AI part together. The exact question was:
 Hey @*** and I are doing parallel pairing :slightly_smiling_face: what is the best way to go about this, to work on the same repo on separate branches or just copy on paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Software Development?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/why-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 19:40:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/why-software-development/</guid>
      <description>So as part of my bootcamp experience Flatiron School requires me to write blog posts. This is a feature that I don&amp;rsquo;t think all bootcamps have but is smart. If I can write about coding then I show a deeper understanding about why I am a job ready developer. We all know that our online presence is part of our &amp;ldquo;resume&amp;rdquo; now as more and more hiring managers are looking at social profiles when making job decisions (even if it&amp;rsquo;s a [legal slippery slope&amp;hellip;][1]).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>