<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on My Flatiron Journey</title>
    <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/general/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on My Flatiron Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Learning Hacks</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/my-learning-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 23:28:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/my-learning-hacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I wanted to share the hacks that I&amp;rsquo;m using to upgrade my life some and increase my mental aptitude to crushing this curriculum. There is a certain amount of mental stamina that has to be maintained on a day to day basis to keep up this pace. So&amp;hellip; here&amp;rsquo;s my brain upgrades/biohacks/etc&amp;hellip; that keep my moving tip top while doing this bootcamp full time and taking care of kids full time. All with links to the best place to buy them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing is my coffee. I start my day off with my take on, Bulletproof Coffee. I currently use Central American Single Origin Organic whole bean coffee from Aldi. The most important thing for me is my coffee being light to medium roast. Nothing dark. I also like whole bean because coffee really does taste &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; better if it&amp;rsquo;s fresh ground. I add to that 1 tbsp of &lt;a href=&#34;http://thrv.me/GWQK6N&#34;&gt;Thrive Market Ghee&lt;/a&gt; and 1 tbsp of whatever I have around to up ketones. I prefer &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2nQOZoe&#34;&gt;Brain Octane Oil&lt;/a&gt; because it definitely is nicer on the insides but also use &lt;a href=&#34;http://thrv.me/pP3hDQ&#34;&gt;Now Foods MCT Oil&lt;/a&gt; or just &lt;a href=&#34;http://thrv.me/c4sQTU&#34;&gt;Coconut Oil&lt;/a&gt; if I have neither of the aforementioned. I blend this all up together. This gets me going and curbs hunger for hours. I also pop a couple &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2ohk6dG&#34;&gt;BioScience Brain Boost&lt;/a&gt; and wash them down with my coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then hopefully do my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gymnasticbodies.com/&#34;&gt;Gymnastic Bodies&lt;/a&gt; Daily Limber routine to get the blood flowing some. I follow that up with some meditation utilizing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calm.com/&#34;&gt;Calm&lt;/a&gt;. I try (but usually fail) to write my daily journal entry utilizing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evernote.com/shard/s34/sh/d31e2f00-610a-4d05-8c6e-44b5e6fd5a75/ee032628c7bcb8547e2bfb7f4bdb681e&#34;&gt;this template&lt;/a&gt; I built in Evernote. I very rarely get all of these things done. However, I try to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m on long coding sessions I supplement in the middle of the day with &lt;a href=&#34;http://thrv.me/WBcGBK&#34;&gt;Four Sigmatic Lion&amp;rsquo;s Mane&lt;/a&gt; which I&amp;rsquo;ve found can really get me going. I have to ensure I&amp;rsquo;m stimulated enough mentally or I start getting distracted trying to keep my brain working hard enough. I also diffuse essential oils in my workspace. Specifically &lt;a href=&#34;http://thrv.me/7YEQ7F&#34;&gt;Lemon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thrv.me/RwiYBf&#34;&gt;Rosemary&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://thrv.me/evMTdr&#34;&gt;Eucalyptus&lt;/a&gt;. All three of those are supposed to help with concentration and mental performance. I find the scents definitely keep me alert if not anything else. Something that I recently ran across is &lt;a href=&#34;https://nootrobox.com/sprint&#34;&gt;Nootrobox Sprint&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m interested to try it out. I might just order the mini bottle for $15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should be it if I remember correctly. If I realize I missed something I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE 3/31/17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I completely forgot about how I listen to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brain.fm&#34;&gt;Brain.fm&lt;/a&gt; whenever I&amp;rsquo;m doing work. It really zones me in more than anything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever listened to. I used to use Spotify playlists but now this is the ONLY thing I&amp;rsquo;ll listen to when I need to concentrate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before I Start Flatiron</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/before-i-start-flatiron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/before-i-start-flatiron/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There were a few things I had to get out of the way before I started Flatiron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I needed a solid schedule I was going to follow. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to take 8 months to finish the program. In fact, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take 8 months to finish the program as my expenses were too much to stretch that long. I also wanted to minimize my family&amp;rsquo;s child care expenses so I came up with a solid schedule:&lt;br /&gt;
M-Th 6am-7am personal care (shower, breakfast, walk dog, etc&amp;hellip;) 7am-8am (or whenever kids wake up) Flatiron. 8am-8pm family/kids. 8pm-10pm Flatiron. 3 hrs/day.&lt;br /&gt;
Fri-Sun 8am-10pm Flatiron (1 hour lunch &amp;amp; dinner). 12 hrs/day.&lt;br /&gt;
Total 53 hours of school per week.&lt;br /&gt;
~800 hours to graduation = 15 weeks.&lt;br /&gt;
This seemed doable as my former career in restaurant management had me working 55 hours standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I needed somewhere to do this work. The house we had just built had a closed in office which was not in use. So I skimmed IKEA&amp;rsquo;s website and picked out a desk and chair. Granted IKEA is 3 hours away from my house so it will be a pain to go pick it up but spending $100 on a desk, chair, and that plastic thing you put on the carpet so a chair can roll seemed like it was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the plan was coming together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>