<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flatiron blog on My Flatiron Journey</title>
    <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/flatiron-blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flatiron blog on My Flatiron Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://itzsaga.github.io/categories/flatiron-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I Deployed My Sinatra App To Heroku</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 23:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/day-051/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MY SINATRA PORTFOLIO PROJECT IS DONE!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can say I&amp;rsquo;m pretty stoked. This blog is part of the requirements though so get ready :-). Actually, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take enough notes to really get into the code in this blog. I did hit some solid stumbling blocks and there is some major refactoring of code needing to happen but I&amp;rsquo;m overall pretty happy. A large part of the time I spent was making the app look good utilizing &lt;a href=&#34;https://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that definitely needs to be refactored is one of my helper methods:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;def current_user_parents
  parents = []
  current_user(session).houses.each do |house|
    Parent.where(house_id: house.id).each do |parent|
      parents &amp;lt;&amp;lt; parent
    end
  end
  parents
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s sandwich code (starts with a variable set to an empty array, fills that array, returns that array) so I know I can most likely eliminate two lines from that or even three if I&amp;rsquo;m not pushing onto that &lt;code&gt;parents&lt;/code&gt; variable anymore. We&amp;rsquo;ll see. I&amp;rsquo;m interested to pick the brain of the instructor that goes over the project with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see what I&amp;rsquo;ll call v0.8 (I figure it&amp;rsquo;s close to v1.0 but not yet lol) at &lt;a href=&#34;https://your-neighbors.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;https://your-neighbors.herokuapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;. I feel like the code is solid but still some functionality and visual things that need to be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to add a static footer to the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a house is deleted the parent and children remain in the database but can never be accessed again because of how I list them in relation to the house they&amp;rsquo;re in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When there are no parents or children I need to add a link suggesting to create some.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user tries to access the info for something they didn&amp;rsquo;t create (ie. they created house 8 but try and go to the link for house 5) the error page tells them to login even though they are logged in. I need to create a different error page for logged in users trying to access stuff that isn&amp;rsquo;t there&amp;rsquo;s vs. the error page when a person isn&amp;rsquo;t logged in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some color!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure I could find more. Feel free to check out the app. Sign up, use it, and report issues to the GitHub link at the top right on every page of the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting deploying to Heroku as well. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a solid guide on deploying a Sinatra app with a DB to Heroku. Through Heroku&amp;rsquo;s docs and this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sitepoint.com/get-started-with-sinatra-on-heroku/&#34;&gt;Get Started with Sinatra on Heroku&lt;/a&gt; from 2013 I got it up and running though. The biggest thing was setting up Postgres and what to put in the &lt;code&gt;Procfile&lt;/code&gt;. Let me see if I can remember what exactly I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;gem &#39;pg&#39;&lt;/code&gt; to your Gemfile. Also, define your version of ruby, ie. &lt;code&gt;ruby &#39;2.4.1&#39;&lt;/code&gt; in your Gemfile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I changed the sqlite gem to development like this &lt;code&gt;gem &#39;sqlite3&#39;, :group =&amp;gt; :development&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I added a &lt;code&gt;config/database.yml&lt;/code&gt; because the Heroku docs said to but I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s needed. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably delete it and see what happens in the near future. The Heroku docs have an example that I used and just changed the &lt;code&gt;database:&lt;/code&gt; names.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;config/environment.rb&lt;/code&gt; is where the magic happened. I kept the &lt;code&gt;:development&lt;/code&gt; environment using sqlite3 because I read in some of the docs that you needed to know the host, username, password, port and something else to make it work locally. I figured if I could get it to work without figuring that out I would do that. I got this working locally running &lt;code&gt;shotgun&lt;/code&gt; and on the Heroku server too. With the changes it now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;require &#39;bundler/setup&#39;
Bundler.require

configure :development do
  ENV[&#39;SINATRA_ENV&#39;] ||= &amp;quot;development&amp;quot;

  ActiveRecord::Base.establish_connection(
    :adapter =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;sqlite3&amp;quot;,
    :database =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;db/neighborhood#{ENV[&#39;SINATRA_ENV&#39;]}.sqlite&amp;quot;
  )
end

configure :production do
  db = URI.parse(ENV[&#39;DATABASE_URL&#39;] || &#39;postgres://localhost/mydb&#39;)

  ActiveRecord::Base.establish_connection(
    :adapter =&amp;gt; db.scheme == &#39;postgres&#39; ? &#39;postgresql&#39; : db.scheme,
    :host     =&amp;gt; db.host,
    :username =&amp;gt; db.user,
    :password =&amp;gt; db.password,
    :database =&amp;gt; db.path[1..-1],
    :encoding =&amp;gt; &#39;utf8&#39;
  )
end

require_all &#39;app&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Procfile&lt;/code&gt; was something I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sitepoint.com/&#34;&gt;SitePoint&lt;/a&gt; article I linked above had this line for it and this is what made it all work &lt;code&gt;web: bundle exec rackup config.ru -p $PORT&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the rest I followed the Ruby docs on Heroku &lt;a href=&#34;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/getting-started-with-ruby#introduction&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the SQLite doc &lt;a href=&#34;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/sqlite3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you get db migration errors you can run rake tasks on Heroku. &lt;code&gt;heroku run rake db:migrate&lt;/code&gt; was one that I needed to do. More in dept docs about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/rake&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, look at that. I remembered way more than I thought. Hopefully this was helpful to someone somewhere. Probably a student coming behind me who is going to pull their hair out trying to get their app to work on Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent today: 8:32&lt;br /&gt;
Time spent total: 198:13&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed today: 1&lt;br /&gt;
Lessons completed total: 406&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Way To Pair Program</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/one-way-to-pair-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 23:07:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/one-way-to-pair-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight a couple people were wanting to know the best way to pair program together. They had both done the beginning parts of the Tic-Tac-Toe with AI project (the one I&amp;rsquo;m getting ready to start) and wanted to work on the AI part together. The exact question was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey @&lt;strong&gt;***&lt;/strong&gt; and I are doing parallel pairing :slightly_smiling_face: what is the best way to go about this, to work on the same repo on separate branches or just copy on paste. She is on IDE, I&amp;rsquo;m on local. Any help muchly appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The always awesome and helpful instructor &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cernanb&#34;&gt;Cernan Bernardo&lt;/a&gt; quickly gave a how-to that I knew others could use. I&amp;rsquo;m just going to abbreviate what he said and turn it into a numbered list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grab each other&amp;rsquo;s SSH URL for your respective GitHub repos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your respective terminals (local or IDE) you would each run the command &lt;code&gt;git remote add upstream *copy_ssh_url_here*&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After running those commands when you run &lt;code&gt;git remote -v&lt;/code&gt; you will see two remotes&amp;hellip;one for your origin which is your respective GitHub repo and one for upstream which is your partner&amp;rsquo;s repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the setup is done, here is the work flow to be done &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; either starts working on the app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;git pull upstream master&lt;/code&gt;&amp;hellip;this will pull down any code your partner has added to the app and pushed up to their GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on your part of the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;git push origin master&lt;/code&gt;&amp;hellip;this will push your new code to YOUR repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that work flow you will each have your code in sync. Just remember to &lt;em&gt;pull before you push&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it. Questions feel free to ask and I&amp;rsquo;ll ask Cernan ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Software Development?</title>
      <link>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/why-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 19:40:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itzsaga.github.io/post/why-software-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So as part of my bootcamp experience Flatiron School requires me to write blog posts. This is a feature that I don&amp;rsquo;t think all bootcamps have but is smart. If I can write about coding then I show a deeper understanding about why I am a job ready developer. We all know that our online presence is part of our &amp;ldquo;resume&amp;rdquo; now as more and more hiring managers are looking at social profiles when making job decisions (even if it&amp;rsquo;s a [legal slippery slope&amp;hellip;][1]).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have assigned topic of, &amp;ldquo;Why did you decide to learn software development?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons I decided to learn software development. Initially, it was because it is the &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo; thing to do these days. Demand is &amp;gt; Supply when it comes to people in the tech industry and overall everything we do now is being run by a computer. The Internet of Things (IoT) needs to be programmed. I truly believe that we are moving to a knowledge economy and very soon (on the grand timeline) most repetetive jobs will be replaced by robots, including driving. See a great post on [automation][2] here. However, people will need to program these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things like bootcamps are popping up like crazy as people are making the jump to be developers. The potential pay and benefits are attractive too. We&amp;rsquo;ve all seen images of massive tech companies and their offices where you can take a break from your bean bag workstation and get a massage from the in house masseuse while listening to a private live Billy Joel concert streamed to your company provided bluetooth Beats headphones. Okay, maybe not that extravagent but you get the idea. Or the person who travels the world making 6 figures and all they need is a laptop and internet. Having that remote work freedom at some point is also attractive. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want this life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another driving force is that I was in hospitality. An industry that is &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; family friendly. 55+ hour weeks are required for salary managers in most instances and nights, weekends, holidays are the busy time. I kept with it by saying I would &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; be in a high enough job title where I would be doing more strategic planning and thus work a more typical 9-5 schedule. I still believe that to be true. Once a person gets to District Manager or F&amp;amp;B Director you check in on early morning and closing operations occaisonally but you could care less &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; the money is counted at close, just that it&amp;rsquo;s counted correctly. If it isn&amp;rsquo;t counted correctly there&amp;rsquo;s always a manager below you to push that to anyways. Something I rarely speak about but through my 10 years in the restaurant business I was laid off 4 times. I was paid severace a couple times and a couple times just collected unemployment but the lack of job stability paired with seeing people 2 years into a tech career making 2x what I was making cemented my interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I dabbled while still working my restaurant job. I learned from [freeCodeCamp][3] the most among many other places. Knowing that I could work on a project for hours without taking a break, then stop for the day, then pick it up two days later, then stop, then get stuck the next day and make zero progress, then two days later finish it off, and LOVING that process cemented in me this is something I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized that on the intellectual front I would always be challenged and have something to learn when it came to software development. I&amp;rsquo;ll never know it all and that is a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how could I make this career transition with a mortgage and 3 kids? In person bootcamps were out of the question. There are two in Nashville (that I know of) and I know people who have graduated from each. First, [Nashville Software School][4] is an awesome program. However, it takes 6 months and we didn&amp;rsquo;t have 6 months of me not working to spare. The other is [The Iron Yard][5] and while they have a solid reputation the approximately $1000/week tuition was not going to work. In addition, I knew I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be out of pocket completely for 12 weeks, my family life would fall apart. So I came across the [Flatiron School Online Web Developer Program][6]. Work at your own pace when you have time, job guarantee, a solid curriculum, and high praise from people in the industry I spoke with. The work at your own pace is what sold me the most. I could code before the kids got up and after they went to bed and all weekend long when my wife was home. I could still take care of my kids all day M-F and we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to pay for a nanny. I could potentially finish in 12-15 weeks (they say the curriculum takes ~800 hours) just like a more traditional bootcamp but spend $6000 instead of $10k+. Boom, now to get in. I applied, did some coding, and got accepted (acceptance rate is ~8% so it&amp;rsquo;s competitive).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ultimately I decided on software development for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It genuinely interests me outside of doing it as a career.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pay ain&amp;rsquo;t bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; schedule so I&amp;rsquo;ll be home for dinner, off on weekends and holidays.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The possibility of working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]&amp;#x3A;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hiring.monster.com/hr/hr-best-practices/recruiting-hiring-advice/acquiring-job-candidates/social-media-recruiting-guidelines.aspx&#34;&gt;http://hiring.monster.com/hr/hr-best-practices/recruiting-hiring-advice/acquiring-job-candidates/social-media-recruiting-guidelines.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]&amp;#x3A;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/bill-gates-and-elon-musk-just-warned-us-about-the-one-thing-politicians-are-too-scared-to-talk-8db9815fd398&#34;&gt;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/bill-gates-and-elon-musk-just-warned-us-about-the-one-thing-politicians-are-too-scared-to-talk-8db9815fd398&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]&amp;#x3A;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.com&#34;&gt;https://www.freecodecamp.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]&amp;#x3A;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nashvillesoftwareschool.com/&#34;&gt;http://nashvillesoftwareschool.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5]&amp;#x3A;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theironyard.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.theironyard.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6]&amp;#x3A;&lt;a href=&#34;https://flatironschool.com/programs/online-web-developer-career-course/&#34;&gt;https://flatironschool.com/programs/online-web-developer-career-course/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>